<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scene on Paul John Cronin</title>
    <link>https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/tags/scene/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scene on Paul John Cronin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/tags/scene/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data visualisation &amp; technical communication</title>
      <link>https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/post/data_visualisation_technical_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/post/data_visualisation_technical_communication/</guid>
      <description>Data visualisation skills includes utilising software and analytical skills to create a graphic record of data that is processed and organised.&#xA;Data visualisation &amp;amp; technical communication is more than just python graphs - it requires communicating technical ideas clearly, effectively. My data visualisation experience includes Tableau, as well as many scientific papers and patents.&#xA;Tableau (Data Visualization) This tableau data exploration was to investigate the claimed link between COVID vaccinations and death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database systems</title>
      <link>https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/post/database_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pauljohncronin.github.io/PJC_DS_Portfolio/post/database_systems/</guid>
      <description>Database systems are more than just a working knowledge of SQL, but include Hadoop, MapReduce, MRJob, Hive and Spark.&#xA;Technical skills are among the hard skills that employers can require when hiring a data scientist. Statistical data, platforms for visualising data, processing software and open-source and closed source programs can be common technical skills that a data scientist may possess.&#xA;Relational Database Design This project was to design a relational database to keep track of bookings for a number of AirBNB locations, and produce a diagram of the tables and the connections between them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
